[Music]
[音乐]
alright welcome to being the session on
好的，欢迎参加
programming in Java 8 my name is
Java 8中的猫编程我的名字是
Venkat Subramanyam I'm going to talk
我要谈一谈Venkat Subramanyam
about function programming in general
关于一般的功能编程
for a little bit and then I'll draw
画一点，然后我画
example from Java 8 to see how Java 8
Java 8的示例，看看Java 8如何
supports some of these Styles I'll also
支持其中一些样式，我也会
make certain distinctions as to a few
对一些做出某些区分
things about functional style versus
关于功能风格与
functional programming so let's get
函数式编程，让我们开始吧
started well one of the really good
很好的开始了，真的很好
things about Java is Java has evolved
关于Java的事情Java已经进化
into supporting functional style of
融入功能风格
programming for a good about 20 plus
编程大约20多个
years Java supported imperative style of
Java支持的命令式风格
programming along with object-oriented
编程以及面向对象
style of programming but now we can
编程风格，但现在我们可以
actually do functional style of
实际做的功能风格
programming also but why should we
也要编程，但为什么要
really care about this
真的很在乎
well functional programming has been
功能良好的编程已经
around for a very long time it's been
已经有很长一段时间了
around for even longer than
周围甚至比
object-oriented programming has been
面向对象的编程已经
around and one of the interesting things
周围和有趣的事情之一
about function programming is it solves
关于功能编程是否解决了
a certain number of problems that have
一定数量的问题
just become imminent over the past
在过去变得迫在眉睫
decade or so so one of the things is the
十年左右的事情之一是
growth of computer applications we are
我们正在发展计算机应用
seeing massive use of computer
看到大量使用计算机
applications we can't have any human
我们没有人的应用
hack activity today that doesn't involve
今天不涉及的骇客活动
computer applications that was not the
不是的计算机应用程序
case of course a few decades ago and
当然是几十年前的事了
then of course when it comes to writing
那当然是写作
code there are two kinds of complexity
代码有两种复杂性
that every one of us deal with one of
我们每个人都应对其中之一
them is inherent complexity inherent
它们是固有的内在复杂性
complexity is the complexity at the root
复杂性是根本的复杂性
of the application the domain and on the
的应用程序域和
other hand a lot of things what we deal
另一方面，我们处理很多事情
with is also known as the accidental
与也被称为偶然
complexity unfortunately though while we
不幸的是，尽管我们
cannot get rid of the inherent
无法摆脱固有的
complexity a lot of what we struggle
复杂性很多我们在努力
with every single day is accidental
每一天都是偶然的
complexity I'm going to make the claim
我要提出的复杂性
that imperative style of programming is
编程的命令式风格是
inherently complex what as functional
本质上复杂的功能
programming has removed that accidental
编程已消除了意外情况
complexity from our shoulders that's one
从我们的肩膀上看那是一个复杂性
of the reasons why this is a better
为什么这更好的原因
programming model for a lot of stuff we
很多东西的编程模型
can do and of course with
可以做到，当然可以
object-oriented programming one of the
面向对象程序设计之一
things we quickly run into is that it
我们很快遇到的是
doesn't quite deal with mutable state a
并没有很好地处理可变状态
very well and shared mutable but it
很好，共享可变，但它
becomes really a problem and of course
变成一个真正的问题，当然
with emergence of multi-core processors
随着多核处理器的出现
we no longer are really dealing
我们不再真正在交易
with multiple threads running on a
在一个线程上运行多个线程
single machine or a single processor
单机或单处理器
multi-threading shears truly is
多线程剪确实是
multi-threaded where multiple threads
多线程，多线程
can and run and of course a program that
可以运行，当然，
may pretend to work correctly on a
可能假装在
single core may actually end up being
单核实际上可能最终被
broken on a multi-core processor so how
在多核处理器上坏了怎么办
do we manage some of these use well one
我们管理好其中一些使用情况吗？
of the biggest problems is mutable state
最大的问题是可变状态
well
好
mutability is something almost everyone
几乎每个人都是可变性
here has done and we don't feel really
这已经做完了，我们真的不觉得
that bad about mutability so mutability
关于可变性的问题太糟糕了
is okay what about sharing well sharing
好的，分享好分享
is a good thing remember what mom told
记得妈妈说的是好事
us to share so mutability is okay
我们分享，所以可变性还可以
sharing is good but shared notability is
共享是好的，但共享的知名度是
devil's work the minute we bring shared
我们带来共享的那一刻，魔鬼的作品
mutability a lot of things can go wrong
可变性很多事情都会出错
comes really hard one of them is it's a
真的很难，其中之一是
very highly error-prone code i remember
我记得非常容易出错的代码
day when a developer came to me and he
有一天开发商来找我，他
said well this code over here is not
说得好，这里的代码不是
working can you take a look at it to be
工作，你可以看看它是
fair it was not a very long piece of
公平，这不是一个很长的
code and and I looked at it quickly and
代码，然后我迅速查看了
I said if you send this input it should
我说如果您发送此输入，应该
give you this output is that I know
给你这个输出是我知道
right but it doesn't so we both were
是的，但是事实并非如此，我们俩都是
straighting staring at it like we are
像我们一样直视它
stupid and after a few minutes I said
愚蠢的，几分钟后我说
wait did you really mean to change the
等等你真的是要改变
input given to this function on this
在此为此功能提供的输入
line number seven he thought for a
他以为第七行
second and he said I'm stupid and he
第二，他说我很愚蠢，他
walked away well a lot of times we don't
很多次我们都走的很好
think about modifying variables it's
考虑修改变量
really hard it becomes error-prone over
真的很难，因为它容易出错
time the code is really hard to reason
时间代码真的很难推理
as well we're struggling to really
以及我们正在努力
understand how this code actually works
了解此代码的实际工作方式
and to explain the code also becomes
并解释代码也成为
very difficult in other words the more
换句话说，非常困难
state change we have in code the really
状态更改，我们在代码中
hard it is to read a reason with that
很难读到一个原因
code and of course wait until somebody
代码，当然等到有人
tells you to make that code concurrent
告诉你使代码并发
and making such a code concurrent is
使这样的代码并发是
incredibly difficult in fact one of the
事实上难以置信的困难之一
really big problems we deal with is the
我们要解决的真正大问题是
structure of the code is very different
代码的结构非常不同
between being sequential and being
在顺序和存在之间
concurrent and that really hurts us get
并发，这真的伤害了我们
performance out of code once we realize
一旦意识到，性能就会超出代码
we have to make it concurrent well
我们必须使其并发良好
function programming solves a lot of
函数编程解决了很多
these things but what is old is new
这些东西，但是旧的是新的
again in fact some of the concepts of
再次事实上，
function programming really was
函数编程真的是
introduced way back in 1929 1930s when
早在1929年1930年代就引入了
the lambda calculus console was
lambda演算控制台是
introduced
引进
of course the some of the first
当然首先
programming languages actually were
编程语言实际上是
functional in nature so this is not a
本质上是功能性的，所以这不是
newfangled idea invented yesterday it
昨天发明了新奇的想法
has been around for a very long time
已经存在很长时间了
just waiting for the industry to grow up
只是在等待行业成长
to make use of some of these ideas but
利用其中的一些想法，但是
one of the central concepts are
中心概念之一是
functional programming is assignment
功能编程是赋值
less programming you may say wait a
更少的编程，您可能会说等待
second are you out of your mind
第二，你不在意
how could you program no assignments so
你怎么不能编程没有作业，所以
I want to draw a parallel to this so we
我想与此平行，所以我们
can get a better perspective on this so
可以对此有更好的认识
if you really look back in time back in
如果您真的时光倒流
the 60s and 70s maybe even into the 80s
60和70年代甚至到80年代
one of the things we really focused on
我们真正关注的一件事
is that four-letter word go-to so I'm
那是四个字母的单词，所以我
going to say go-to is too structured
说去太过结构化
programming and in in other words this
编程，换句话说，
is something we've been really hammered
这是我们真正受到打击的东西
with is not to use go tooth let's
与不使用去牙让我们
entertain the thought just for a minute
待一会儿
Here I am in Java code I'm going to go
这是我要使用的Java代码
ahead and call a little thing called
往前叫一个小东西
blah well very carefully notice what
很好，非常小心地注意到什么
this says to us it says that error not a
这对我们说它说错误不是
statement just keep that in mind blah is
声明只是记住，等等是
not a statement well I'm going to change
不是声明，我要改变
this to go to well we know that go-to is
这个很好，我们知道
evil we shouldn't use it good old
邪恶，我们不应该使用它
Dijkstra told us gotas are evil don't
迪克斯特拉告诉我们，哥达人是邪恶的，不要
use it so I'm using go-to here in Java
使用它，所以我在Java中使用了转到此处
but when I run it notice Java doesn't
但是当我运行它时，注意到Java并没有
say not a statement instead Java says
说不是声明而是Java说
illegal start of expression what that
非法开始表达那是什么
mean well Java says go-to is a valid
Java表示Go-to是有效的
keyword but I dare you to use it so it's
关键字，但我敢于使用它，因此
a forbidden keyword they don't want us
他们不想要我们的禁止关键字
to use the keyword okay that's great but
使用很好的关键字，但是
I want to really go ahead and run this
我真的要继续进行
little code I'm going to take a very
小代码，我将采取非常
simple example here well we know that we
简单的例子在这里，我们知道我们
cannot use go-to we shouldn't use go-to
无法使用定位，我们不应该使用定位
if somebody even suggest using go-to
如果有人甚至建议使用转到
will frown on them all that is great but
会为他们皱眉，但是很棒
I'm going to go ahead and say far int I
我要说的很远
equal to zero I less than 10 and then
等于零，我小于10，然后
I'm going to of course just do a very
我当然要做一个非常
trivial simple loop here I plus plus in
简单的循环在这里我加加
this case of course I'm going to say if
这种情况我当然要说
I is greater than 5 then output the
我大于5然后输出
variable I so no big deal at all but
变数我所以没什么大不了的，但是
this we know as structured programming
我们称之为结构化编程
it's structured program
它是结构化的程序
because we got nice structuring of the
因为我们对
code we are stacking up the code one
代码我们正在堆积代码一
after the other and there is a good
一个又一个又一个好
entry point there's a good exit point
入口点有一个很好的出口点
hey that's all really making sense
嘿，这真的很有意义
that's basically what we would call a
基本上这就是我们所说的
structured programming but what I'm
结构化编程，但我是
going to do here though is I'm going to
虽然我要去这里做
go to the command line and say Java P
转到命令行并说Java P
minus C and minus C is already an alias
减C和减C已经是别名
on my machine so I won't provide that
在我的机器上，所以我不会提供
and then I'm going to say classes right
然后我要说正确的课程
here and sample and let's take a look at
在这里采样，让我们​​看一下
the bytecode and what a surprise if you
字节码，如果您感到惊讶
look at the bytecode being generated
看看正在生成的字节码
what do you see over there go to in the
您在那边看到了什么
bytecode hey wait a minute did we say
字节码嘿，等一下我们说
that in a structured program we
在结构化程序中
shouldn't use go twos well go tools are
不应该使用合二为一的工具
like matches you I'm sure everyone here
喜欢比赛，我确定这里的每个人
has matches at home we all use matches
家里有火柴，我们都用火柴
but you don't go to the kids and say
但你不要去孩子们说
kids I'm going to go take a shower here
孩子们，我要去这里洗个澡
are some matches for you to play with
有一些比赛供您玩
well we use matches but matches are for
我们使用火柴，但是火柴是为了
adults to use not for children's to play
大人不要给孩子玩
with case in point
以案例为例
go to is exactly the same so a
去是完全一样的，所以
structured program will have go to
结构化程序将转到
except that we will not have go to in
除了我们不会去
our code there could be go to act layers
我们的代码可能会起作用
below so in a very similar way when we
下面以非常类似的方式
say assignment less programming we're
说我们少分配编程
not saying there's no assignments period
不说没有作业期
we are saying that just like we don't
我们在说，就像我们不
use go to we won't use assignments but
使用转到，我们将不使用分配，但
just like assignments just like go to
就像任务一样
can happen under the hood assignments
可以在引擎盖下完成
may happen under the hood as well so
也可能在引擎盖下发生
assignments are easy to assignment is to
作业很容易分配
functional programming so this is a way
函数式编程，这是一种方法
to draw the distinction that go-to is
得出区分是
the structured programming like
结构化的编程像
assignments these two functional
分配这两个功能
programming that is the evil part of the
编程是邪恶的一部分
what we are trying to avoid like we try
我们尝试避免的事情
to avoid go to instructor programming we
为了避免去讲师编程，我们
try to avoid assignments in a functional
尽量避免在功能中分配
programming but a lot of times I use the
编程，但是很多时候我使用
word explicit assignment rather than
单词显式分配而不是
assignment meaning we don't do
分配意味着我们不做
assignments but it could happen under
作业，但可能发生在
the hood in in layers below well the
罩在井下面
next thing is of course dealing with
接下来的事情当然是处理
immutable state we don't want to be
不变的状态，我们不想成为
mutating the state instead we want to
改变状态相反，我们想要
transform the state as much as you can
尽最大可能改变状态
and because transforming the state
而且因为改变国家
becomes a lot more easier to reason and
变得更容易推理和
work with than mutating the state
工作而不是改变状态
but obviously one question remains
但显然还有一个问题
Kyra's oh my gosh if you're going to be
凯拉，如果你要成为我的天哪
dealing with immutable state would you
处理不可变状态，你会
not base performance by copying objects
不能通过复制对象来提高性能
over and over and over well let's think
一遍又一遍，让我们想一想
about something really in parallel here
关于真正平行的东西
again version controls have been doing
版本控件又在做
this for a long time when you deal with
这很长一段时间，当您处理
the version control you check in files
您签入文件的版本控制
the version controls don't make a full
版本控制功能不完整
copy of the files obviously what they do
文件的副本显然是做什么的
is they make very nice smart copying
他们做得很好吗？
where they keep the differences around
他们保持差异的地方
so in other words we do smart copying
换句话说，我们进行智能复制
rather than through copying or full
而不是通过复制或完整
copying in a similar way languages and
以类似的方式复制语言和
tools and libraries can do this for us
工具和库可以为我们做到这一点
when we make a copy of an object it
当我们复制对象时
doesn't have to be a full copy it can be
不一定要是完整副本
a very efficient copy a case in point is
一个非常有效的例子就是
one example is tries where it rises a
一个例子是尝试上升的地方
data structure quite widely used in
数据结构在
languages like a closure and Scala where
像闭包和Scala这样的语言
twice make a very smart copy of objects
两次制作非常智能的对象副本
minimally on copy on-demand and that
按需复制最少
becomes really efficient likewise
同样变得非常有效
libraries can also be smart about how
图书馆也可以很聪明
they handle data so they can minimize
他们处理数据，以便他们可以最小化
these garbage objects being created in
这些垃圾对象在
between so there are ways to really save
之间，所以有一些方法可以真正保存
performance while achieving these goals
在实现这些目标的同时表现
as well but one of the most important
也是最重要的之一
things to think about is functions are
要考虑的是功能
considered as first-class citizens so
被认为是头等公民
what does that really mean functions are
这真正意味着功能是什么
first class citizens well what it means
头等舱公民好意思
is it's so far what we have done is we
到目前为止，我们所做的是
can't pass objects to functions well
不能很好地传递对象
sure we can create a in this case
确保我们可以在这种情况下创建一个
objects within within functions and then
功能内的对象，然后
finally of course we can't return
最后，我们当然不能返回
objects from functions so we are used to
函数中的对象，所以我们习惯了
doing these things for for a long time
做这些事很久了
but what if we treat functions as
但是如果我们将函数视为
first-class citizens we can start
一流的公民，我们可以开始
treating them and moving them around and
对待他们并四处移动
passing them around so in other words
换句话说，将它们绕过
these are called higher-order functions
这些被称为高阶函数
so what is a higher-order function well
那么什么是高阶函数
a higher-order function typically is
高阶函数通常是
going to take this idea that we talked
我们将接受这个想法
about but in addition to doing the
关于，但除了
object composition we can also do
我们也可以做对象合成
function composition so if you look at
功能组成，所以，如果你看
the higher-order functions higher-order
高阶函数高阶
functions can pass functions to
函数可以将函数传递给
functions as well not just objects they
以及它们不仅作用于对象
can create fun
可以创造乐趣
functions within functions and of course
功能内的功能，当然
they can also return function from
他们还可以从
functions as well so those become what
也可以发挥作用
are called higher-order functions that
被称为高阶函数
you can work with very effectively so we
您可以非常有效地与我们合作，因此我们
can do up decomposition or object
可以分解或对象化
decomposition but we can also do
分解，但我们也可以
function decomposition as well but one
功能分解也一样
of the most important things to keep in
要保留的最重要的东西
mind is that functions don't have side
介意的是功能没有边
effects I want to emphasize that for a
我想强调的是
minute because it's easy to miss this a
分钟，因为很容易错过这个
little bit so I want to emphasize that
我想强调一点
functions have to be pure well what does
功能必须是纯正的
it mean to be pure meaning pure
意思是纯正的意思是纯正的
functions don't have side effects so
功能没有副作用，所以
side effects well what are side effects
副作用好是什么副作用
then well in this case there are two
那么在这种情况下，有两个
points we need to consider and I would
我们需要考虑的几点，我会
argue that the first point is a lot easy
认为第一点很容易
for a lot of us but the second point is
对于我们很多人来说，第二点是
not that intuitive the first thing is a
不是那么直观，第一件事是
pure function does not change anything
纯函数不会改变任何东西
so we can all relate to that of course
所以我们当然可以与之相关
the function is modifying something well
功能修改得很好
that's not pure but there's an important
那不是纯粹的，但是有一个重要的
rule here does not depend on anything
规则在这里不依赖任何东西
that changes as well so in other words a
也会发生变化，换句话说，
pure function should not make any
纯函数不应该做任何
changes but it shouldn't depend on
变化，但不应该依赖
anything that changes as well well the
任何变化的东西以及
first rule I think is pretty clear to
我认为第一条规则很清楚
most of us it's quite obvious you don't
我们大多数人很明显你不
want to mess with data you don't want to
想要弄乱您不想要的数据
change share data that's obvious but if
更改明显的共享数据，但是如果
I say that a pure function should not
我说纯函数不应该
depend on anything that changes we're
依靠任何改变我们的东西
like why well the reason is one of the
就像为什么原因是其中之一
critical features of functional
功能的关键特征
programming is that functions can be
编程是功能可以
lazy and if you're depending on
懒惰，如果你依赖
something that changes outside your
在你之外改变的东西
function cannot be lazily evaluated
功能不能被懒惰地评估
we'll see some of this later on when we
我们稍后会看到其中的一些
look at some examples along the way so
看一路上的一些例子
having said this what are really the
说了这到底是什么
benefits of this one of the biggest
最大的好处之一
benefits is that it becomes easier to
好处是它变得更容易
work with the code it reduces accidental
使用代码可以减少意外
complexity in code quite often that is
代码的复杂性经常是
one of the biggest benefits but I want
最大的好处之一，但我想要
to draw the distinction between
区分
functional style versus purely
功能风格与纯粹风格
functional programming languages a
函数式编程语言
purely functional programming language
纯函数式编程语言
will not allow any mutability period a
将不允许任何可变期a
functional style language often
经常使用功能风格的语言
suitability at the risk of we failing to
适应性可能会导致我们无法
do the right things so it puts a burden
做正确的事情，所以会加重负担
on you rather than protecting you but it
在你身上而不是保护你，但是它
provides higher-order functions so in
提供高阶功能，因此
other words you can say if the language
您可以说的其他语言
provides higher-order functions it's a
提供高阶功能
function of style language if a language
语言的功能，如果一种语言
goes to the extent of limiting
达到限制的程度
mutability in addition to providing the
可变性，除了提供
functional the higher-order functions
功能高阶功能
then it becomes a purely functional
然后就变成了纯粹的功能
language for example Java and a lot of
语言，例如Java和很多
other languages are functional style
其他语言都是功能样式
languages like like Haskell for example
例如像Haskell这样的语言
is a purely functional language because
是一种纯粹的功能性语言，因为
they provide higher-order functions but
它们提供高阶功能，但
they don't also permit mutability but
他们也不允许变异，但
what are some of the real benefits of
有什么真正的好处
this we're going to be looking at state
这是我们要看的状态
transformation rather than state
转变而不是状态
mutation so we take their data and
变异，所以我们获取他们的数据，
transform through the states rather than
通过国家而不是转变
mutating the state but let's look at
改变状态，让我们看一下
what this really means to us in some
在某些情况下这对我们真正意味着什么
context let's say before we go any
我们先说一下上下文
further with this let's consider methods
进一步讲一下方法
so what in the world is a method method
所以世界上是一种方法
it is a function after all which often
毕竟这是一个功能
belongs to a class or to an object so
属于一个类或对象，所以
that's what we call as a method in Java
这就是我们在Java中称为方法的东西
a method is a function but but that
方法是一种功能，但那
function often belongs to either a class
函数通常属于一个类
or it belongs to an object but on the
或它属于一个对象，但在
other hand a function has four things
另一方面，功能有四件事
well what are the four things a function
那么功能的四件事是什么
typically has the first thing it has is
通常拥有的第一件事是
the name of a function so we celebrated
函数的名称，所以我们庆祝了
we give names for functions the second
我们给第二个函数命名
thing it contains often is a return type
它经常包含的东西是返回类型
will we tell what this what is the
请问这是什么
function return the third thing is a
函数返回的第三件事是
parameter list and of course the last
参数列表，当然还有最后一个
thing of course is the body of the
当然是身体的
function so that's what a function
功能，这就是功能
typically contains when we write them so
通常包含在我们编写它们时
let's look at an example of using a
让我们来看一个使用
method or a function suppose I were to
方法或函数假设我要
say thread is equal to new thread and
说线程等于新线程，并且
then of course I'm going to say thread
那我当然要说线程
darts start over here and then I'm going
飞镖从这里开始，然后我要去
to simply say in main over here and we
在这里主要说一下，我们
can see that in main just popped up but
可以看到主要弹出
of course I want to do something in
我当然想在
another thread so we say new runnable
另一个线程，所以我们说新的可运行
over here and then once I create the
在这里，然后一旦我创建了
runnable I'm going to say public void
我要说的是公共无效
run and then with them does run method
运行，然后与他们一起运行方法
of course I'm going to say nyan another
我当然要再说一遍
let's say a node or a thread so in this
比方说一个节点或线程
case of course we will run this function
当然，我们将运行此功能
and we can see that in main popped up
我们可以看到主要弹出
first and then an end of the thread once
首先，然后线程的结束一次
that kick thread kicked in it said that
踢进去的踢线说
that's going to run but if you look at
那将会运行，但是如果你看
this code line number 16 he is a method
此代码行号16他是一个方法
which is the run method we lack that run
这是我们缺少的运行方法
method with unrunnable and then we pass
不可运行的方法，然后我们通过
it to the thread class we've been doing
它到我们一直在做的线程类
this for a very long time of course but
这当然很长时间了
imagine you are boarding an airplane and
想像您正在登机，
they tell you you can only take two
他们告诉你你只能吃两个
items with you and you cannot take more
物品，你不能再拿更多
than two items so what are the two items
比两个项目那两个项目是什么
you're going to pick from here well what
您将从这里很好地选择
do you think is the most important item
你认为最重要的项目吗
here the one you cannot board without
在这里，你不能没有一个
obviously that will be the body of the
显然，这将是
function without the body of the
没有主体的功能
function there's no point doing this
功能是没有意义的
well yeah you've selected one item you
是的，您选择了一项
got only one more item you can select
只有一个项目可以选择
well obviously what good is having the
好吧，显然有什么好处
body if you don't have the data to work
身体，如果您没有工作数据
with so you have to have the parameter
用，所以你必须有参数
looks to be given to you and that's it
看起来会给你，仅此而已
you're out of limits you can only take
您超出限制，只能接受
two things
两件事情
and that's exactly what lambda cans do
那正是lambda罐头所做的
lambda expressions essentially have only
Lambda表达式本质上只有
those two things it's got a parameter
这两个东西有一个参数
list first of all an arrow that
首先列出一个箭头
separates the body from the parameter
将主体与参数分开
list that is the structure of a lambda
清单是lambda的结构
expression so a lambda expression has
表达式，因此lambda表达式具有
minimal at the very minimum a parameter
最小，最小参数
list and a body well what about the
清单和身体很好
return type the return type is inferred
返回类型推断返回类型
based on the context here you don't have
根据这里的上下文，您没有
to say the return type what about the
说返回类型怎么样
name of the method who cares when the
谁在乎的方法名称
work is done it's anonymous so lambda
工作完成了，所以匿名
expressions are anonymous methods whose
表达式是匿名方法，其
return pipes are inferred and all you
返回管道被推断出来
carry with you is a parameter list an
随身携带的是参数清单
arrow and the body of the function so
箭头和功能的主体所以
what I'm going to do here is take this
我要在这里做的就是
example right here that worked a minute
这个例子在这里工作了一分钟
ago but I'm going to go ahead and
前，但我要继续
rewrite this this time but this time I'm
这次改写这个，但是这次我
going to remove all the ceremony around
要删除所有的仪式
it notice that's pure noise that I've
它注意到那是我的纯净噪音
highlighted so I remove that noise put a
高亮显示，所以我消除了噪音
little arrow right there
那里的小箭头
and then I'm going to remove the
然后我要删除
remaining noise from here and so we
从这里剩下的噪音，所以我们
converted the code to use a lambda X
将代码转换为使用Lambda X
version rather than using an anonymous
版本而不是使用匿名
function anonymous method anonymous
函数匿名方法匿名
class so in this case the thread is
类，所以在这种情况下，线程是
actually a constructor which is a
实际上是一个构造函数
higher-order function the thread says
线程说的高阶函数
you don't have to pass an object to me
你不必把东西传给我
of runnable it's okay if you pass a
可以运行，如果您通过了
function to me which has no name and
对我来说没有名字的功能
that function of course is the lambda
该功能当然是lambda
expression that we are passing to this
我们传递给这个的表达
function so in this case you can see
功能，在这种情况下，您可以看到
that we passed a function which takes no
我们传递了一个不需要
parameters and then of course the arrow
参数，然后当然是箭头
and the body which is printing that
和正在打印的主体
message so we were able to pass this
消息，所以我们能够通过
method so for the first time in a long
长期以来第一次的方法
time
时间
we've been able to treat the function as
我们已经能够将函数视为
a first class citizen so what that means
头等公民，这意味着什么
is it's kind of like we've been creating
就像我们一直在创造
functions like they're kindergarteners
像他们是幼儿园的功能
the function comes to you this little
功能就这么少
code comes to you and says could I go to
代码来找你，说我可以去吗
the neighborhood park please you said no
社区公园，请你说不
sweetie you cannot go alone let me send
亲爱的你不能独自一人让我发送
an adult with you and we have been
和你一起成人，我们一直
wrapping it now you can free that and
现在包装它，您可以释放它，并且
you can send it away on its own so I've
您可以自行发送，所以我已经
been creating functions as a first-class
创造一流的功能
citizen now in Java 8 moving forward
Java 8中的公民现在向前迈进
with the functional style of programming
具有编程的功能风格
so what does leads us to is we can do
所以导致我们去做的是我们可以做的
some really powerful things with this
一些非常强大的功能
let's quickly look at an example of how
让我们快速看一下如何
we can reap some of these benefits let's
我们可以从其中获得一些好处，让我们
go to what we have been doing for a very
去我们一直在做的非常
long time which is a very traditional
很久很传统
looping so I got a list of numbers 1 to
循环播放，所以我得到了1到1的数字列表
10 right here and what I want to do is
10就在这里，我想做的是
loop through these so I could say for I
通过这些循环，所以我可以为我说
equal to 0 I less than and the number
等于0我小于和数字
star and then you pass and ask is it
星，然后您通过并询问是
sizes that length is it count
大小就是长度
because obviously we can't have a
因为显然我们不能
standard isn't it if it's a array it's a
标准不是它，如果它是一个数组，它是一个
length if it's a ArrayList it's a size
长度，如果是ArrayList，则为大小
go figure
去搞清楚
so then we could say plus plus and then
所以我们可以说加号再然后
we pass again as the question is it less
我们再次通过，因为问题少了
than or less than or equal to because we
小于或小于或等于，因为我们
are never sure about it and then of
永远不确定，然后
course to add insult to injury I got to
当然要加重对我的伤害
say numbers again and do a get and get
再说一遍，做得到
the data out of it well this is a very
数据很好，这是一个非常
high ceremony but if you look at this
隆重的仪式，但如果你看着这个
code I'm going to argue this is a very
代码，我要说这是一个非常
complex code you may say wait a minute
您可能会说复杂的代码，请稍等
did you say complex isn't this a simple
你是说复杂不是那么简单吗
for loop oh no this is not a simple for
循环哦，不，这不是简单的
loop it's a familiar for loop
循环是一个熟悉的for循环
it's important not not to get confused
重要的是不要混淆
with the terms the words simple and
用简单和
familiar are very different from each
每个人都很熟悉
other this is not a simple for look it's
其他这不是一个简单的外观
a complex but familiar for look so what
复杂但熟悉的外观
is familiar similar is something we have
熟悉，这是我们拥有的东西
looked at several times we don't
看了几次我们不
probably care to look at it again and
可能想再看一遍
something that we know very well and
我们非常了解的东西
this is a very familiar for loop but I'm
这是一个非常熟悉的for循环，但是我
going to argue this is complex in fact
要说这实际上很复杂
it's very easy to prove it's complex
证明它很复杂很容易
because there is something already very
因为已经有一些东西
simple we could say int element in
很简单，我们可以说int元素在
numbers and then we could of course
数字，然后我们当然可以
output the element right off the bat so
立即输出元素，因此
you can see that while both of the code
您可以看到，两个代码
produce exactly the same result this one
产生与此完全相同的结果
is a lot simpler than the previous one
比上一个简单很多
these two collectively are known as
这两个统称为
external iterators but we can use what's
外部迭代器，但我们可以使用
called an internal iterator instead so
叫做内部迭代器
what we can do in here is we can do
我们可以在这里做的是我们可以做的
internal iterators moving forward and
内部迭代器向前发展，
what that means is we can say rather
这意味着我们可以说
than iterating through this this way we
而不是通过这种方式进行迭代
could simply say well numbers dot for
可以简单地说井号代表
each well let's stop right there and
每个井，让我们就停在那里
talk about this for a second notice in
谈论这个，在第二次通知
the earlier example we were passing the
我们通过的较早的示例
number too far and we know one thing
数字太远，我们知道一件事
about code structures like this they are
关于这样的代码结构
never polymorphic on the other hand the
另一方面，永不多态
minute you say numbers dot for each that
分钟，你说每个数字点
you know is polymorphic because the
你知道是多态的，因为
implementation of for each can change
的实现可以改变
depending on the runtime implementation
取决于运行时的实现
of the collection you are dealing with
您正在处理的集合中的
so that's a benefit already that you are
所以你已经是一个好处
carrying with you but what we can do
随身携带但我们能做什么
with this is you can now say for each
有了这个，您现在可以针对每个
and then you can say new consumer
然后你可以说新消费者
integer and then of course in this case
整数，然后在这种情况下当然
I'm going to say public void except the
我要说的是公共无效
integer value or element E and then we
整数值或元素E，然后我们
could output this element right there
可以在那里输出这个元素
so in this case you can see the output
所以在这种情况下，您可以看到输出
is exactly the same as before we didn't
与我们之前没有的完全一样
have to use an external iterator we used
必须使用我们使用的外部迭代器
an internal iterator now the benefit of
内部迭代器的好处是
this code is you are telling what to do
这段代码是你在告诉做什么
and not how to do it you're focusing on
而不是专注于
what to do per iteration you're putting
您要放置的每次迭代该做什么
the iteration on autopilot and of course
自动驾驶仪上的迭代，当然
you can enjoy polymorphism
你可以享受多态
all of these things are good good things
所有这些都是好东西
but I know what you're thinking you're
但是我知道你在想什么
thinking if all that really good but to
在想如果真的很不错但是
leave that benefit if I have to use yet
如果必须使用，请离开该福利
another anonymous inner class heck no
另一个匿名内部类
well sure but that's the beauty of this
当然可以，但这就是它的美
we don't have to we can take this one
我们没有必要我们可以拿这个
right away and say well rather than
立即说出好话而不是
working so hard we can remove all the
如此努力，我们可以删除所有
ceremony from here only keep the essence
从这里举行的仪式只保留本质
out of this and then we can remove the
从这个，然后我们可以删除
rest of the part as well and you can see
其余部分也可以看到
the code still works right here so what
该代码仍然在这里工作，所以
we can do in this case is we can get rid
我们可以做的就是摆脱
of all that noise in the code these are
在代码中所有这些噪音是
called
叫
functional interfaces I always chuckle
我总是笑的功能接口
and I hear the word functional interface
我听到功能界面一词
because I wonder if there are some
因为我想知道是否有一些
interfaces that are functional what
具有功能的接口
about the other points are they
关于其他几点
dysfunctional but in in essence it
功能失调，但实质上
basically in this case where were a
基本上在这种情况下
single abstract method interface is
单个抽象方法接口是
expected you are callable
期望你可以打电话
or enables the consumer in this case
或在这种情况下使消费者受益
file filter anywhere a single abstract
任何地方的文件过滤器都只有一个摘要
method interface is expected you can now
现在可以使用方法界面
pass of course lambda expression very
当然可以通过lambda表达
easily that's what we just did but we
这就是我们刚刚所做的，但是我们
can go a let's step further and improve
可以让我们更进一步并改善
this even further if you will now look
如果您现在再看一下
at this code for a second we are saying
在这段代码中，我们说的是
here is a lambda given an integer I'm
这是给定一个整数的lambda
going to go ahead and print that integer
继续打印该整数
but let's take a wild guess if you are
但是让我们大胆猜测一下
iterating over a collection of the
迭代一个集合
integers you put your hand into this
您将手放在此整数
collection and pick an element in your
收集并选择您的元素
wildest imagination can you imagine what
最疯狂的想象力你能想象什么
you would pick from a collection of
你会从一个集合中选择
integers a dog a monkey well of course
当然，让狗成为猴子的整数
it will be an integer so you know it's
这将是一个整数，所以你知道
an integer the language knows it's an
语言知道它是一个整数
integer
整数
why bother seeing or the typist so for
为什么要打扰或打字员
the first time in a long time
很久以来的第一次
Java is finally intelligent we can use
Java终于可以使用了
very easily type inference with lambda
使用lambda轻松键入推断
expressions so you can simply leave out
表达式，这样您就可以省去
the type because the type is not adding
类型，因为类型未添加
any value in this case it is kind it is
在这种情况下，任何值都是友善的
very obvious now make no mistake this is
现在非常明显，不要误会，这是
not dynamic typing this actually is
不是动态输入，这实际上是
static typing where the type is inferred
推断类型的静态类型
at compile time just to verify that if I
在编译时只是为了验证我是否
go back to this code and
回到这段代码，
on the element II if I were to call foo
如果要调用foo，则在元素II上
notice the error message we are getting
注意我们收到的错误消息
it says method foo variable e of type
它说方法foo类型的变量e
integer and so it very clearly knows
整数，所以它很清楚地知道
that ease of integer there is absolutely
整数的难易度绝对是
no confusion in this point so we don't
在这一点上不要混淆，所以我们不要
have to really specify the type in this
必须在此指定类型
case but we can go a step further again
情况，但我们可以再走一步
in this if you will now that we know
在此如果您现在就知道
that this is an integer we don't have to
这是一个整数，我们不必
say the type well we can also get rid of
说好类型，我们也可以摆脱
that silly parentheses so if you only
傻括号，所以如果你只
have exactly one element being given to
正好有一个要素
your lambda you can get rid of that type
你的lambda，你可以摆脱这种类型
the parenthesis as well so if you don't
括号也是如此，如果您不
have any parameters you have to put a
有任何参数，您必须将
parenthesis if you have two or more
如果您有两个或多个，请加上括号
parameters you have to put a parenthesis
您必须加上括号的参数
but if you just only have one you don't
但是如果你只有一个，那就没有
have to really specify that but one more
必须明确指出，但还要
improvement if you look at this code
如果您看这段代码，将会有所改善
that we have at hand
我们手头有
notice that in this case we receive an E
请注意，在这种情况下，我们收到E
and we print it and we could have done T
然后我们将其打印出来，就可以完成T
plus 1 for example or we could have done
例如加1，否则我们可以完成
e times 2 for example but the point is
e例如2倍，但要点是
we didn't and all we are doing is
我们没有，我们正在做的是
receiving the data and simply passing it
接收数据并简单地传递它
and this kind of lambda is extremely
这种lambda非常
trivial in that it receives an argument
琐碎的是它收到一个参数
a parameter and either passes it down to
参数，然后将其传递给
another function or invokes our method
另一个函数或调用我们的方法
on it I've got a special name for these
在上面我有个特别的名字
kinds of lambdas I've called these
我称为这些的lambda
lambdas are as the office space pattern
lambdas是作为办公空间模式
if you remember watching the office
如果你记得看办公室
space movie hey Tom what do you do in
太空电影，嘿，汤姆，你在做什么
this company I take the requirements of
我接受这家公司的要求
the program programmers and give it to
程序程序员并将其交给
from the manager from the business
来自业务经理
people and I give it to the programmers
人，我把它交给程序员
so all the tom was doing in this company
所以汤姆在这家公司所做的一切
was he was taking the requirements from
他是从
the business people and giving to the
商人和给予
programmers effectively really no
程序员实际上真的没有
purpose well when you have a lambda
当你有lambda的时候很好地使用
which is not doing really a lot other
这实际上并没有做很多其他事情
than simply transforming the data you
不仅仅是转换您的数据
are going to get tired writing this and
写这个会很累
you're going to say this code is stupid
你会说这段代码很愚蠢
but history I shown one thing to us Java
但是历史我向我们展示了一件事Java
programmers never write stupid code they
程序员永远不会编写愚蠢的代码
instead develop IDE is to vomit stupid
相反，开发IDE是要呕吐愚蠢
code and people will be asking each
代码，每个人都会问
other what should I do that you're using
其他我该怎么办
to do this well they know this was
为了做到这一点，他们知道这是
coming so they remove this duplication
来，所以他们删除了这个重复
so if you notice we have a e over here
所以如果你注意到我们在这边
so this ski is common so we'll remove it
所以这把滑雪板很普通，所以我们将其删除
with this e right here and then we'll
有了这个e在这里，然后我们将
remove this arrow as well and we simply
也要删除此箭头，我们只需
change this dock to double : and these
将这个基座更改为double：
are called
叫做
method references method references make
方法参考方法参考
the code lock easier to understand and
代码锁更容易理解和
work with I'm going to say method
我要说的方法
references take a little bit more effort
参考需要更多的努力
to write them when you get before you
在你来之前写它们
got used to them but method references
习惯了，但是方法参考
often are easier to read so they are
通常更容易阅读，所以它们
easier to read then right in the
更容易阅读，然后在
beginning but over time we get really
开始，但随着时间的流逝，我们真的
better at it as we use it so what we did
我们在使用它时会更好，所以我们做了
in this example is we took a external
在这个例子中，我们采取了外部
iterator the one that we had before and
迭代器，我们以前有一个
we refactored it a few times here is the
我们重构了几次，这是
traditional external iterator that we
我们传统的外部迭代器
started with we got something simpler
首先我们得到了一些简单的东西
which is also an external iterator then
这也是一个外部迭代器
of course we took the internal iterator
当然我们采用了内部迭代器
which was verbose but showed us how we
这很冗长，但向我们展示了我们如何
can do the looping and print stuff
可以进行循环并打印内容
inside this loop and then finally of
在这个循环中，最后
course we traded that with lambda
当然我们用lambda进行交易
expressions we got rid of the type and
表达式，我们摆脱了类型和
use the type inference we got rid of the
使用我们摆脱的类型推断
parentheses after that and then of
之后的括号，然后是
course eventually we use the method
当然最终我们使用该方法
reference because this particular lambda
参考，因为这个特定的lambda
was that simple so this gives you an
就是这么简单，所以这给你一个
idea about how we can go about using
关于如何使用的想法
lambda expressions to start writing
Lambda表达式开始写作
these kinds of code moving forward so
这些代码向前发展
this becomes a very fundamental shift in
这成为一个非常根本的转变
how we do this but one of the things to
我们如何做到这一点，但要做的事情之一
keep in mind is this is essentially a
请记住，这本质上是
way of programming where we favor more
我们更喜欢的编程方式
of a decorative style of code than first
的装饰风格比第一
and then a functional way of doing so
然后是一种实用的方法
what is decorated style a decorated
什么是装饰风格
style of coding is where you tell what
编码风格可以告诉您什么
to do and you let the underlying
去做，你让底层
functions figure out how to do it in an
函数找出如何做到这一点
imperative style of code you spend your
命令式的代码风格
time and if we're telling what to do and
时间，如果我们告诉该怎么做，
also how to do it let's look at one
还有怎么做让我们来看一个
example of this to get a better feel for
这个例子可以更好地理解
what that really means so here is a list
真正的意思是，所以这里有一个清单
of numbers 1 to 10 but let's say the
1到10的数字，但假设
given problem is find the total of
给定的问题是找到总数
double of even numbers so we were asked
偶数的两倍，所以我们被问到
to find the total of
找出总数
even numbers you normally do to create
通常创建的偶数
this in the imperative style well first
这首先是命令式的
of all you would say result is equal to
您会说结果等于
zero and when you are done you want to
零，当您完成后，您想
print out the result but then you say
打印结果，然后您说
over here for int element coming from
这里的int元素来自
numbers and then you say if element here
数字，然后你说如果元素在这里
mark 2 is equal to 0 then of course
标记2等于0那么
you're going to say the result is equal
你会说结果相等
to e times 2 but then you have to put a
到e乘以2，但随后您必须放一个
break out of it to break out of this
打破它打破这一点
loop well in this case of course well
在这种情况下当然循环良好
actually in this case we want to find
实际上在这种情况下，我们想找到
the total of all the numbers so no break
所有数字的总和，所以不间断
here so we got to make all these
在这里，我们必须做所有这些
decisions and then we have to say plus
决定，然后我们不得不说加
equal to so you can run through it well
等于所以您可以顺利通过
in this case goes total of double of all
在这种情况下，总计为总数的两倍
the even numbers in the collection but
集合中的偶数，但
we have written code like this for ever
我们永远都这样写过代码
but if you look at this code anyone
但是如果你看这段代码的话
heroes with print code like this before
像以前这样打印代码的英雄
well of course every one of us but the
当然，我们每个人，但
question is how do you feel when you
问题是当你感觉如何
write code like this dirty right really
像这样写代码真的很脏
dirty in fact after day long work after
脏了实际上是经过一天的漫长工作之后
writing this code you go home and the
编写此代码，您就可以回家了
kids coming run come running towards you
孩子们跑来跑向你
you say don't touch me
你说不要碰我
I gotta go shove her first because this
我得先推她，因为
is very low-level coding we have to be
是非常低级的编码，我们必须
doing over we can do this again but
做完了，我们可以再做一次，但是
before we do this let's talk about two
在我们这样做之前，让我们先讨论两个
different things two different smells of
不同的东西两种不同的气味
imperative code the first smell is we
命令性代码的第一个气味是我们
got a variable we defined over here but
有一个我们在这里定义的变量，但是
we can we are mutating that variable
我们可以改变那个变量
over and over and over that's one of the
一遍又一遍，这是其中之一
smells of imperative style of coding is
命令式风格的气味是
we do mutability quite often the second
我们经常做可变性
thing is you have to spend your effort
事情是你必须花力气
telling not only what to do but also
不仅告诉做什么，而且告诉
saying how to actually do this well on
说如何实际做到这一点
the other hand we can rewrite this code
另一方面，我们可以重写这段代码
this time but I'm going to say output
这次，但我要说的是输出
will start with numbers over here dart
从这里的数字开始
stream think of stream as an internal
流认为流是内部的
iterator and then we can say filter and
迭代器，然后我们可以说过滤器和
I'm going to say given an element e
我要说的是给定元素e
return the elements only that are even
返回仅偶数的元素
and not any of the other elements so in
而不是其他任何元素
this case we applied a filter we do a
在这种情况下，我们应用了过滤器
map given an element element times two
给定一个元素的地图乘以两倍
and of course finally I'm going to say
最后我当然要说
go ahead and give me a sum operation on
继续给我一笔总和运算
the L
L
results and return the result to me well
结果并将结果很好地归还给我
if you look at this code both of those
如果你看这两个代码
code produce exactly the same result but
代码产生完全相同的结果，但是
there is some really key difference
确实有一些关键的区别
between these two kinds of code the top
这两种代码之间的顶部
code is of course imperative in nature
代码本质上当然是必不可少的
we tell what to do and how to do and we
我们告诉做什么和怎么做，我们
also have mutability in the code if you
如果您在代码中也有可变性
look at the code in the bottom I'm going
看看我要在底部的代码
to say the code in the bottom is very
说底部的代码非常
humane no variable was tortured in the
人道的，在
making of the result so we're not
结果，所以我们不是
mutating any variables repeatedly the
反复变异任何变量
second thing is if you look at the code
第二件事是，如果您看一下代码
in the top you have to say every single
在最上面，你必须说每一个
detail you had to say get one element at
你不得不说的细节
a time please check is that element
一段时间请检查是那个元素
either even go ahead and double that
甚至可以继续加倍
element right here then fetch the
元素就在这里，然后获取
current value of result then add to the
结果的当前值，然后添加到
value of result and then store it into
结果的值，然后将其存储到
the result you have to say every single
结果你必须说每一个
thing this code is like talking to a
这段代码就像和
toddler well the first time you talk to
第一次和孩子聊天
a toddler is very exciting you're going
小孩会让你兴奋
to say wow this was awesome talking to
说哇，这真棒
the toddler well the next thing you
小孩好，接下来你
realize you got to say the same thing
意识到你必须说同样的话
over and over you're going to say well
一遍又一遍你会说的很好
walk slowly hold it with both hands look
双手慢慢抬起
where you're going don't step on the cat
你要去的地方不要踩猫
on the way you're going to be having to
在您将不得不
say this and then you realize this is
说这个然后你意识到这是
going to go on for the next 18 years
接下来的18年
that's called parenting isn't it well
那叫做育儿不好吗
that's how it feels when you start
当您开始时就是这样
writing code with imperative style on
用命令式风格编写代码
the other hand the functional style
另一方面功能风格
feels like you're talking to and
感觉就像你在和
responsible adult that is one of the
负责任的成年人是
biggest benefits you get out of this is
您从中获得的最大好处是
a very nice way to transform so given a
一种非常好的转换方式，因此
collection of numbers get me the
数字集合让我
collection which is only even numbers
只有偶数的集合
double the values and total so the code
将值和总数加倍，因此代码
begins to read like a problem statement
开始读起来像问题陈述
it removes the accidental complexity
它消除了意外的复杂性
that usually is inherent in code that's
通常是代码固有的
one of the biggest benefits you get so
您获得的最大好处之一
what are some of the differences in the
有哪些区别
imperative style you focus on how to do
势在必行的风格
things whereas in a decorative and
东西，而在装饰和
functional style you focus on what to do
您专注于功能样式的事情
mostly you encourage mutability in a
大多数情况下，您鼓励
imperative style you transform data in
命令式风格，您可以在其中转换数据
functional and decorative you often deal
您经常处理的功能性和装饰性
with side-effects when it comes to
带有副作用
imperative style you write pure
你写的命令式纯
functions when it comes to a decorative
装饰功能
and functional notice each of these
和功能注意这些
functions are pure they don't change the
函数是纯函数，它们不会改变
word
字
around them they are not dependent on
在他们周围，他们不依赖
anything that's mutable that's what
任何易变的东西
these do along the way and of course you
这些一路走来，当然你
pass objects in this case you can pass
在这种情况下可以传递对象
functions as well and then finally the
以及功能，最后
code is very hard to compose an
代码很难组成一个
imperative style because statements
命令式风格，因为陈述
often cost mutability and you got to go
通常会花费可变性，因此您必须离开
back and get the data whereas functions
返回并获取数据，而函数
nicely compose and you can transform
很好地组合，您可以进行变换
data from one to the next to the next to
数据从一个到另一个到另一个
the next but I want to deviate a little
下一个，但我想偏离一点
bit from this and talk back into
一点点回头再说
functional style about lambdas and
关于lambda和
closures for just a minute so going back
关闭一分钟，所以回去
to this example let's take values 1 2 3
在本例中，我们取值1 2 3
for a minute and in this case what I'm
一分钟，在这种情况下，我是
going to do is I'm going to ask for the
我要做的是要
values to be doubled first of all and
值首先要加倍
print it so in this case I'm going to
打印它，在这种情况下，我要
say numbers dart stream and then I'll
说数字飞镖流，然后我会
say map given an element element times 2
说给定一个元素的地图乘以2
and then for each I'm going to say
然后我要说的每个
system dot out and print illan while
系统点出并打印错误
looking at this code for a second look
再看一下这段代码
at this line alone if you will here is a
仅此一行，如果您要在这里
lambda if I ask you what 2 is 2 is a
lambda如果我问你2是2是
literal of course what in the world is e
当然，字面意思是e
e is a parameter to the lambda much like
e是lambda的参数，很像
args is a parameter to main e is a
args是main e的参数
parameter to this lambda expression
此lambda表达式的参数
well this lambda is very self-contained
那么这个lambda是非常独立的
it's happy it caught everything it needs
很高兴它抓住了所有需要的东西
not a problem on the other hand if I
另一方面，如果我没有问题
were to say factor over here well if you
要说的是这里的因素，如果你
look at this code if I ask you what is e
看这个代码，如果我问你什么是电子
it's very clear what eat is e is the
很清楚e是什么东西
parameter to this lambda what in the
这个lambda的参数在
world is this factor well the fact that
世界就是这个因素，事实是
of course is not defined within this
当然没有在此定义
lambda so this lambda has to look for
lambda，所以这个lambda必须寻找
this factor so this lambda well I'm
这个因素，所以我很好
going to put this down here so this
要把这个放到这里
lambda has to close over its defining
lambda必须结束其定义
scope so defining scope looking for the
范围，因此定义范围寻找
variable factor to bind to so in other
绑定到其他变量中
words this lambda has to close over try
这个lambda必须关闭的单词尝试
saying the word close over really fast
说这个词真的很快结束了
several times now you know what a
好几次，你知道
closure is so a lambda does not have
闭包是这样的lambda没有
state so I'm going to say lambdas are
状态，所以我要说的是lambda
stateless
无状态的
on the other hand what about a closure
另一方面，关闭
closure has the immutable state and so
闭包具有不变的状态，因此
you want to make sure that it's actually
您想确保它实际上是
immutable that's very critical so
一成不变的，所以非常关键
closures carrying a state with them
带有状态的关闭
lambdas are pretty stateless and so what
Lambda非常无状态，那又如何
a closure can do is a closure and
封闭可以做的是封闭
capture a state where you are defining
捕获您正在定义的状态
it and carried over to the point of
它并延续到
execution waiting at this code but let's
执行等待这段代码，但让我们
quickly take a look at this right here
快速在这里看看
this lambda is defined right here in the
这个lambda是在这里定义的
main then you call the map method within
main，然后在其中调用map方法
the map method you could either call the
您可以调用map方法
lambda or you can pass the lambda down
lambda或您可以将lambda传递给
few more levels and you may call the
还有几个级别，您可以致电
lambda after that so in other words the
lambda之后，换句话说，
lambda that's defined in the main may
在主要的may中定义的lambda
actually get executed at one or two or
实际上在一两个或两个执行
three levels from below the stack but
从堆栈下面的三个级别，但是
when it's executed in that stack level
在该堆栈级别执行时
below it needs a variable defined up
下面需要定义一个变量
here so that is where it captures the
在这里，这就是它捕获
context from here and carries it down
从这里开始的背景，并把它带下来
there for availability so that is
那里有空房，所以
basically what a closure s so one of the
基本上是封闭的，所以其中之一
things we should keep in mind is
我们应该记住的事情是
closures carry state but it's important
闭包带有状态，但是很重要
for us to make sure that the state that
让我们确保状态
is carried by the closures are immutable
由封闭带是不可变的
now why is it so important that the
现在为什么如此重要
closure states are immutable well to
闭包状态对于
understand that let's go ahead and do
了解我们继续前进
this a little differently
这有点不同
I'm going to go ahead and bring in the
我将继续进行
stream over here so I'm going to say
流过这里，我要说
scream dart scream and I'm going to say
尖叫，飞镖尖叫，我要说
stream off the integer right here here
从这里的整数流掉
and then is equal to numbers dot scream
然后等于数字点尖叫
but I'm going to say dot map give an
但我要说的是点图
element I'm gonna say element x factor
我要说的元素x因子
and then of course in this case I'm
然后当然在这种情况下
going to say that given the stream dot
会说给定流点
for each
每个
I'm going to go ahead and say system dot
我要继续说系统点
out and print Len and I'm going to go
列印Len，我要走了
ahead and print the string well that's
前面并正确打印字符串
good so far but where is the factor I'm
到目前为止还不错，但是我在哪里
going to say in this case this factor is
在这种情况下，要说的是
int factor is equal to 2 so the code
整数因子等于2，所以代码
actually in this case is taking the
实际上在这种情况下
factor n and
n和
making a product out of it so that
用它来制造产品
obviously worked but one thing to keep
显然有效，但要保留一件事
in mind is look at this closure for a
想到的是看一下这种关闭
minute well this closure definitely is
分钟好，这个关闭肯定是
not modifying any particular variable so
不修改任何特定变量
that is good it satisfies the first rule
很好，它满足了第一条规则
of purity it doesn't change anything
纯粹不会改变任何东西
what about the second rule of purity
那第二条纯净规则怎么办
remember the second rule of purity is it
还记得纯洁的第二条法则吗
doesn't depend on anything that changes
不依赖于任何变化
oh wait a minute it does depend on
哦，等等，这取决于
factor but one of the beautiful things
因素，但美丽的事物之一
about Java is that it treats these as
关于Java的是，将它们视为
what are called effectively final so in
所谓的有效最终
other words you could put the word final
换句话说，你可以把单词final
right here in this case if I say factor
在这种情况下，如果我说因素
equals four notice you get an error
等于四个注意，您会得到一个错误
right there on line 15 and it says you
就在第15行，它说你
cannot change factor because its final
无法更改因子，因为其最终
but what if I remove this final from
但是，如果我从中删除此决赛
here well in old versions of Java until
在Java的旧版本中都很好，直到
Java 7 you have to put final you have a
Java 7您必须将最终的
local variable which is accessed from
从以下位置访问的局部变量
within an inner class Java 8 changes the
内部类Java 8中的更改
rules just a little bit in Java 8 you
在Java 8中只是一点点规则
don't have to put final now you may say
您不必说现在就进入决赛
wait a minute
等一下
why don't have I have to put final well
为什么没有我必须把最后的好
Java 8 says you and I have been going
Java 8说你和我一直在
out for a long time we can trust each
长期以来我们可以信任每个人
other just a little bit so as long as
其他只要一点点
you know how to behave you don't have to
你知道怎么做，你不必
go through the ceremony of putting final
进行决赛的仪式
so as a result when I write this code
因此当我编写这段代码时
this is called effectively final however
这实际上称为最终
if you come here and say factor equals 4
如果你来这里说因子等于4
immediately Java screams and says I
Java立刻大喊，说我
thought we had an understanding between
以为我们之间有一个了解
us and you are now violating that
我们和你现在违反了
contract this is why it's called
合同，这就是为什么它被称为
effectively final in other words you
换句话说，有效地最终
cannot access a variable a local
无法访问本地变量
variable if you are mutating it well
如果您很好地变异它
this is a good news this is when Java is
这是一个好消息，这是Java
trying to protect you in this case
在这种情况下试图保护您
languages like Haskell are purely
像Haskell这样的语言纯粹是
functional languages there is no
功能语言没有
assignment if you tried something very
如果你尝试了一些非常的事情
similar to this in c-sharp or
与此类似，在c-sharp中
javascript are a few other languages
javascript是其他几种语言
those languages will not stop you Java
这些语言不会阻止您使用Java
is trying to be protective here and says
在这里试图保护自己并说
no no no don't do that that's not a good
不，不，不，那不是一个好习惯
programming practice don't do that well
编程实践做得不好
that's a good idea so far but you know
到目前为止，这是个好主意，但您知道
how some programmers are they will roll
他们将如何发展一些程序员
up their sleeves and say let me tell you
袖手旁观，说让我告诉你
how to really cheat Java these are very
如何真正欺骗Java这些非常
dangerous people usually but what you
危险的人通常，但是你
can do potentially in this case is
在这种情况下可以做的是
because Java doesn't all of you to
因为Java并不全都
change factor you may get tempted to say
您可能会想说的改变因素
in square bracket factor equals new int
方括号中的因子等于new int
and then you could put a two right here
然后你可以在这里放两个
at this point job is gonna say good luck
在这一点上，工作要说好运
and be quiet so when you run this code
保持安静，所以当您运行此代码时
of course you got factor zero but if I
当然你有零因子，但是如果我
go back here and say factor zero is
回到这里说零因子是
equal to zero notice in this case Java
在这种情况下等于零通知Java
will no longer complain Java will
将不再抱怨Java
probably sit there and keep laughing and
可能坐在那里继续笑，
sale there's going to be fun watching
特卖会很有趣
these this code but in this case it
这些代码，但在这种情况下
won't protect you anymore this is also
不再保护您，这也是
true if this was a member variable a
如果这是一个成员变量，则为true
field in your class Java is no longer
Java中的字段不再
going to protect however keep in mind
要保护，但要牢记
this lambda disclosure is a bad closure
此lambda披露是错误的结局
because it's no longer pure why is it no
因为它不再是纯净的，为什么不
longer pure because remember the two
不再纯净，因为记住这两个
rules of purity a pure function should
纯函数的纯净规则
not change anything that's good but a
不会改变任何好的东西，但是
pure function should not also depend on
纯功能也不应依赖
anything that changes well clearly this
任何明显改变的东西
depends on something that changes in
取决于变化的东西
fact the reason this is really a
其实这真的是一个原因
terrible code is you can take this code
糟糕的代码是您可以接受此代码
make make a pinup photo of this and show
为此制作一个封面照片并显示
it to different people and ask them
给不同的人问
what's going to be the output I - you're
我的输出将是什么-你是
going to get different answers from the
从中得到不同的答案
people and some of them will tell you
人，其中一些人会告诉你
well because two-factor 0 is - this is
很好，因为二因子0是-这是
going to be the double of the values
将是价值的两倍
other people may say because factor is 0
其他人可能会说因为因子为0
now it's going to be 0 but which one is
现在它将是0，但是哪个是
it the right answer is should we really
正确的答案是我们真的应该
be doing such programming because if you
做这样的编程，因为如果你
are trying to write code like this this
试图写这样的代码
is hard to reason error-prone very
很难推理容易出错
difficult to work
很难工作
this is also known as bad idea so don't
这也被称为坏主意，所以不要
do this so this is the reason why the
这样做是因为这就是为什么
purity of functions is so important we
功能的纯度是如此重要，我们
don't want to be messing with things
不想惹事
like this we want to preserve the purity
这样我们要保持纯度
of closures that becomes extremely
的封闭变得非常极端
important so we shouldn't mix the
重要的，所以我们不应该混用
impurity with these but this also
与这些杂质，但这也
illustrates the point about lazy
说明了懒惰的要点
evaluation so let's talk about lazy
评价，所以让我们谈谈懒惰
evaluation got an entire talk on lazy
评价引起了关于懒惰的整个话题
evaluation tomorrow but I'll simply
明天评估，但我会简单地
merely scratch the surface right now
现在只是刮擦表面
notice that on line 13 we had a lambda
请注意，在第13行，我们有一个lambda
expression sitting on line 13 that
坐在第13行的那个表情
lambda expression on line 13 did not
第13行上的lambda表达式没有
execute right now as you walk over line
当您越过线路时立即执行
13 during execution instead it waits
13执行期间改为等待
until you come to line 17 and that's
直到您到达第17行，
when that line 13 is executing that is
当第13行执行时
lazy evaluation or deferred execution it
延迟评估或延迟执行
says I don't need to be doing this now
说我现在不需要这样做
well functional programming cares a lot
函数式编程非常重要
about this so I'm going to go ahead and
关于这个，所以我要继续
say here if somebody comes to you and
在这里说如果有人来找你，
says are you a fan of object-oriented
说你是面向对象的粉丝吗
programming you say oh I love object of
编程你说哦我爱的对象
the programming well why do you care so
编程很好你为什么这么在乎
much of an object into programming well
很多对象都很好地编程
don't get me wrong
不要误会我的意思
things like abstraction and
像抽象和
encapsulation are extremely important
封装非常重要
but you're not programming an
但是你不是在编程
object-oriented system just for extract
仅用于提取的面向对象系统
or encapsulation the real real power of
或封装了
object programming is polymorphism after
对象编程是多态之后
all isn't it so polymorphism is -
都是吗，所以多态是-
object-oriented programming so in other
面向对象的程序设计
words this is what we really are after
话说这就是我们真正追求的
now we all can agree you cannot enjoy
现在我们都可以同意你不能享受
polymorphism without abstraction you
没有抽象的多态你
cannot enjoy polymorphism without
没有它就无法享受多态
encapsulation but polymorphism is what
封装但多态性是什么
we really are after an abstraction and
我们真的是在抽象之后
encapsulation really makes it possible
封装确实使它成为可能
so polymorphism is to optical
所以多态性是光学的
programming like and I'm going to say
像这样的编程，我要说的是
lazy evaluation evaluation is to
懒惰评估评估是为了
[Music]
[音乐]
evaluation is to functional programming
评估是对函数式编程
of course if you're going to have lazy
当然如果你要偷懒
valuation you cannot have lazy
估值你不能偷懒
evaluation without immutability that's
没有不变性的评估
exactly what we saw in this example
正是我们在本例中看到的
because what is immutability do
因为什么是不变性
amiability says this function will not
和可亲的，说这个功能不会
modify anything and it is not depending
修改任何东西，这并不取决于
on anything that will change so you can
在任何会改变的东西上
run it now you can find it later or run
现在运行它，您可以稍后找到它或运行
never run it at all well if it is a
如果它是
impure function you are urgent to run it
功能不完善，您迫切需要运行它
you're going to say run it fast run it
你会说运行它快运行它
now before the world changes and you're
在世界改变之前，你
going to be in a hurry all the time and
会一直很忙
you ask the question when did this run
你问这个问题什么时候运行的
did it run before the change or after
它是在更改之前还是之后运行的
the change you can completely defeat the
您可以完全击败的变化
purpose so you cannot be lazy without
目的，所以如果没有
being having immutability and laziness
具有不变性和懒惰
is an extremely important thing because
是一件非常重要的事情，因为
laziness leads to efficiency in code
懒惰导致代码效率
because you're not sitting there and
因为你不坐在那里
making copies and copies of objects you
制作和复制对象
can defer execution until a much later
可以将执行推迟到以后
time and have those executed very nicely
时间，让他们执行得很好
that's one of the biggest benefits you
那是你最大的好处之一
get out of this so to wrap this up one
摆脱这个，所以把这个包起来
of the real powers in this is laziness
真正的力量是懒惰
but with laziness also comes this
但是懒惰也来了
ability to what's called function
所谓功能的能力
pipelining our function composition
流水线我们的功能组成
function composition is a very powerful
功能组成非常强大
pattern we saw examples of this earlier
模式，我们之前看到了这样的示例
but let's revisit this so suppose I had
但是让我们重新审视一下，假设我有
a collection of numbers with me let's
跟我一起收集数字
say collection on numbers a collection
用数字说集合
of numbers 1 to 10 and I wanted this
1到10的数字，我想要这个
time say a get be a double of square
时间说是平方的两倍
root of let's say of even numbers
我们说偶数根
well I can write this in a very nice
好吧，我可以写一个很好的
flowing pattern so what I can do is I
流动的模式，所以我能做的就是
can say output but this time I can say
可以说输出，但是这次我可以说
numbers start stream and then I can say
数字开始流，然后我可以说
well filter give an element give me
好过滤器给一个元素给我
element mark 2 is equal to 0 then I can
元素标记2等于0，那么我可以
say dot map and Matt Squire root after I
在我说点图和Matt Squire扎根之后
am interested in finding the square root
有兴趣找到平方根
of these and then of course this is
这些，当然，这是
going to be mapped to double this time
这次将被映射为两倍
and then finally I can say darts sum and
最后我可以说飞镖和
then of course one
那当然一
so I totally I can simply return it well
所以我完全可以把它还好
if you look at this code this time
如果您这次看这段代码
though what we have done in this case is
尽管我们在这种情况下所做的是
we are saying given the collection of
我们说的是鉴于
numbers get me only the even numbers but
数字只能让我得到偶数，但
give me the square root of those even
给我那些的平方根
numbers and then find the sum of it and
数字，然后求和
you can see how this begins to flow
您可以看到它如何开始流动
through this becomes what's called a
通过这个变成了所谓的
function composition you'll go through
您将要完成的功能组合
transformations you take the collection
您选择的转换
you transform to even numbers to a map
您将偶数转换为映射
to double to performing the Sun well
加倍表现出色
this is a function composition but the
这是一个功能组合，但是
evaluation is also pretty lazy so what I
评价也很懒，所以我
mean by the evaluation is lazy is until
意思是评估是懒惰的，直到
you hit the sum operation these
你打总和这些
operations are not going to execute and
操作将不会执行，
then minimally they're going to execute
然后他们最少要执行
whatever is necessary so the efficiency
一切必要，所以效率
is big then furthermore in languages
那么大，然后是语言
like Java one of the cool things about
像Java一样很酷的事情之一
this is it is not taking a collection
这是不是要收集
and creating an intermediate collection
并创建一个中间集合
and then yet another intermediate
然后是另一种中间体
collection it's not going to be doing
收集它不会做的
that for you instead it's very efficient
对你来说这是非常有效的
in knowing that these intermediate
在知道这些中间
collections are really not needed first
确实不需要先收集
of all they're not available they're not
所有他们不可用，他们不是
visible outside so internally it doesn't
在外部可见，因此在内部不可见
waste performance by creating all those
通过创建所有这些来浪费性能
garbage collections internally it
内部垃圾收集
directly gets you to the result in the
直接将您带到结果中
end so efficiency is big then it is
结束，所以效率很高，那就是
really hard for it to be efficient
要提高效率真的很难
without laziness as well in fact when
其实也没有懒惰
the terminal operation some is called
终端操作有些叫做
that's when it performs the operation
那就是它执行操作的时间
and because of that it can be efficient
因此，它可以高效
it is not wasting its time and effort
这不是在浪费时间和精力
building all these intermediate results
建立所有这些中间结果
along the way that you get out of this
一路摆脱困境
so the benefits of doing this is first
所以这样做的好处是第一
of all you get cold clarity when you
当您
look at the code you're not going back
看一下你不回头的代码
it's trying to figure out what this code
它试图找出这段代码
is doing you're able to just loop the
在做你就可以循环
follow this code think about this for a
按照此代码考虑一下
minute if I give you a for loop with an
分钟，如果我给你一个for循环
if condition and a bake and I continue
如果条件和烘烤，我继续
and I give you this code and ask you
我给你这个代码问你
tell me what this code is doing and
告诉我这段代码在做什么，
here's a challenge for you give an
这是您面临的挑战
imperative code to somebody to ask them
要求别人问的命令性代码
what does this go do and sit in front of
这是做什么的，坐在前面
them
他们
and what's their eyeball and their
他们的眼球和他们的眼神是什么
eyeball is going to do this it's going
眼球会做到这一点
to start in the top look at the code and
首先从顶部看代码
it's going to do this and then it does
它会这样做，然后它会
this that point is called quite a
这一点被称为相当
confusion right it's like I don't know
困惑吧，就像我不知道
what this code is doing but look at the
这段代码在做什么，但请看一下
functional code you go through a single
您只需一次完成功能代码
pass through it given the collection get
通过它给定的集合得到
me all even numbers find the square root
我所有偶数都找到平方根
of them and total you're doing a single
他们，总的来说，你正在做一个
pass through it that becomes very clear
通过它变得非常清楚
to understand you also have fewer errors
了解您也减少了错误
in code because a the code is doesn't
在代码中，因为代码不是
have accidental complexity in it second
其次是偶然的复杂性
reason why there are fewer errors is
错误更少的原因是
there is less mutability in code as well
代码中的可变性也较少
and that reduces errors also so less
而且减少错误的可能性也降低了
complexity less mutable favors a fewer
复杂性越少，可变性越少
errors in code it also removes all the
代码中的错误也会删除所有
extra garbage variables we have to carry
我们必须携带的额外垃圾变量
around and so it becomes hard to reason
周围，​​所以变得很难推理
you can remove that as well and finally
您也可以删除它，最后
the code becomes easier to paralyse as
代码变得更容易瘫痪
well if you are taking an imperative
好吧，如果你有必要
code with shared mutability and you tell
共享可变性的代码，您告诉
them to make the code concurrent that's
他们使代码并发
really hard because structure of the
真的很难，因为
code changes a lot between sequential
顺序之间的代码变化很大
and concurrent on the other hand with
而另一方面
this kind of code imagine this was a
这种代码想象这是一个
very fairly large collection what you
非常大的收藏
can do is when you run the code you can
可以做的就是在运行代码时
see that it produces the result but you
看到它会产生结果，但是你
can simply throw a parallel in here and
可以简单地在这里扔一个并行
this will run in parallel and produce
这将并行运行并产生
the result across the course either you
整个课程的结果
can call parallel like this or you can
可以像这样并行调用
turn this into a parallel stream as well
也将其转换为并行流
but the beauty of this more important is
但更重要的是
the code structure is not different
代码结构没有不同
between sequential and parallel the
在顺序和并行之间
chord structure for the first time in a
和弦结构首次出现在
long time is exactly the same between
长时间之间是完全一样的
sequential and concurrent that's a huge
顺序和并发这是巨大的
benefit for us to enjoy and that is one
让我们享受的好处，这就是其中之一
of the biggest benefits tells us to
最大的好处告诉我们
summarize functional programming removes
总结函数式编程删除
accidental complexity from our code well
代码中的意外复杂性
clearly we can all agree functional
显然我们都同意功能
programming takes a lot more effort to
编程需要花费更多的精力
understand the beginning that's because
了解开始是因为
we're not familiar with it we are
我们不熟悉我们
familiar with imperative style of
熟悉命令式
programming but once they become
编程，但一旦成为
familiar it takes us a lot less effort
熟悉它可以减少我们的工作量
to write
来写
it removes these accidental complexity
它消除了这些意外的复杂性
it makes it easier to reason the code it
它使代码推理更加容易
makes it easier to penalize the code so
使得惩罚代码更容易
all that benefit we can enjoy that's one
我们可以享受的所有好处就是
of the reasons why we want to favor this
我们为什么要赞成这一点的原因
and it's really cool that most of the
而且真的很酷
mainstream languages today are providing
当今主流语言正在提供
this including Java 8 if you're
这包括Java 8
interested in downloading the code
有兴趣下载代码
examples I showed you you're most
我告诉你的例子
welcome to download them at the link
欢迎通过链接下载它们
that's shown in the bottom hope that was
在最下面的希望中显示了
useful thankful thanks for your time
有用的感谢您的时间
[Music]
[音乐]